ZUHAIB HUSSAIN BUTT

DATA SCIENTIST







https://zuhaibbutt786-zuhaibhussain-butt-resume-a

SUMMARY

Data Scientist familiar with gathering, cleaning and organizing data for use by technical and non-technical personnel. Advanced understanding of statistical, algebraic and other analytical techniques. Highly organized, motivated and diligent with significant background in Different programming Language such as R,Python and Matlab. Expert in machine learning and large dataset management. Demonstrated success in identifying relationships and building solutions to business problems.

SKILLS

- Python
- Hadoop Environment
- Streamlit S
- FastApi
- SparkHive
- Flume
- Cassandra
- R

Shiny

MySQL

- Microsoft OfficeMATLAB
- ce Tableau
 - Power BI
- Spark Arduino IDE

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lab Instructor

GIFT University, Gujranwala, 2021 - current

- Create and taught Labs at undergrad level
- Experience in Intro to data science ,Data mining, Data warehouse, Big Data analytics ,Data visualization ,Data science with MATLAB subjects
- Worked with program director to develop and implement successful lesson plans.
- Observed students to assess progress with lab work and assign grades.
- Demonstrated skills and tools to students during lab sessions.
- Facilitated student participation by delivering fun, engaging lessons.

Data Analyst

ATC, Gujranwala, 2020 - 2021

- Produced monthly reports using advanced Excel spreadsheet functions.
- Created various Excel documents to assist with pulling metrics data and presenting information to stakeholders for concise explanations of best placement for needed resources.
- Documented effective and replicable methods for extracting data and organizing data sources.
- Identified, analyzed and interpreted trends or patterns in complex data sets.

Machine Learning Engineer

Intellicode • 2020 – 2021 (Remote)

- I have worked on several projects in which I used data visualization and machine learning techniques to extract meaningful insights from large datasets
- My goal is to use my skills in data analysis and software engineering to drive business decisions and help organizations to make datadriven decisions
- I am highly motivated, result-oriented individual, who is always eager to learn new things and challenging projects.

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Science

University of Engineering and Technology-Lahore • 2022–2024(expected)

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

GIFT University -Gujranwala • 2017–2021

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Science With Python

udemv

Computer Vision

udemy

streamlit udemy

Matlab

mathworks

SKILLS

- Technical Analysis
- Programming
- Multitasking Abilities
- Self-Motivated
- Planning and Coordination
- Active Listening
- Analytical and Critical Thinking
 Decision-Making

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Covid case study using folium

- Conducted a comprehensive case study on the impact of COVID using Folium.
- Visualized and analyzed pandemic data to provide insights into the geographical spread and severity of cases.

Roman Urdu prediction using machine learning models

- Developed and implemented machine learning models to predict Roman Urdu text.
- Achieved accuracy and efficiency in predicting Roman Urdu, contributing to language processing advancements.

Common Disease Prediction using Machine Learning

- Successfully applied machine learning techniques to predict common diseases.
- Developed a model that assists in early detection and proactive healthcare measures.

Simple Automatic-web-scraper

- Designed and implemented an automatic web scraper.
- Streamlined data extraction from websites, demonstrating efficiency in data collection and automation.

TelecomOptiXcel

- Created and delivered labs at the undergraduate level in the TelecomOptiXcel project.
- Contributed to the understanding and application of data science and analytics in the telecommunications domain.

Laptop-price-prediction-with-streamlit &

- Developed a predictive model for laptop prices using Streamlit.
- Implemented an interactive and user-friendly interface for predicting laptop prices based on various features.

Traffic-sign-classification-and-detection

- Implemented a model for the classification and detection of traffic signs.
- Contributed to the development of technologies for enhancing traffic safety and automation.



"In God we trust, all others must bring data." - W. Edwards Deming